Isaac Muhumuza

isaac.muhumuza@live.co.uk | 41 Ufton Road | London, England, N1 4HE | 07873159550

Summary

An IT consultant / programmer with experience in building innovative RESTful APIs that expedite organizational success. An extensive background in information technology in military computer systems. 5+ years in network management working for the British Armed Forces. A hard worker with an innovative mind and a keen attitude to learning new skills and technologies.

Professional Skills

Expert
Advanced

Additional Skills

Network Infrastructure Management Beginner
Software development lifecycle Beginner
Incident Resolution Beginner
Client Engagement Beginner
Training and Mentoring Beginner

Employment History

CGI

Consultant / Developer

July 2015 - Present

Part of a team developing micro services to support the MOD and BEIS clients.

- Created Spring RESTful APIs that were successfully delivered as product increments at the end of each sprint.
- · Consistently executed continuous integration and delivery using tools such as Git and Jenkins
- Practiced Agile methodologies during development
- Coded to specific coding standards i.e. peer review, Sonar cube code quality metrics.
- Practiced workflow tracking using Jira Management Software

Part of a technical team providing SAAS to financial clients like RBS.

- Co-ordinated directly with clients to understand requirements
- Delivered technical support to all upgraded applications
- Executed and tested implementation specific configuration tasks during application development and upgrade
- Improved application upgrade efficiency by formulating VBA scripts to automate client data migration onto new system
- Enabled non-English language integration by performing application localization and code translation table analysis

Part of a team that provided transitioning of NHS staff to secure networks.

- Enriched user experience through daily client engagement during transition.
- Provided application support on new client network
- · Investigated escalated incidents and provided resolution during the transition period
- Carried out after care support following on from transition

Barclaycard Head Office

Solutions Architecture Intern

June 2014 - September 2014

Summer internship to gain insight into technology. I learnt about the different technical disciplines and experienced the project development stages involved within each technical sector.

HM Forces, Salisbury, England

Network Manager

September 2005 - August 2012

Responsible for the management and deployment of military network systems to enable vital communication during operations to Afghanistan and Iraq

- Accounted for all IT systems and equipment.
- Managed the deployment, set-up, maintenance and repair of secure networks.
- Monitored staff usage and delivered support with network applications.
- Trained 20+ junior engineers on systems maintenance and operation

Education

King's College London, University of London, London, England

Master's Degree, Enrolled

September 2019

MSc Advanced Software Engineering with Management

University of Northampton, Northampton, England

Bachelor's Degree, Graduated

May 2015

BSc (Hons) Computing (Software Engineering)

University of Northampton, Northampton, England

High School Diploma, Graduated

May 2014

HND Computer Science

Memberships

BCS, The Chartered Institute of IT, Professional Member 990638772

Hobbies & Interests

- Volunteer at local sporting arena
- Keen interest in Technology
- Running and regular gym activities
- Football for a local club
- Various other sports; basketball, volleyball and tennis
- Travelling theatre music and films

References

Reference available upon request